

MECU Mihai-Sorin

Passionate Full-Stack developer searching for a remote job

Over 17 years of experience in domains like Logistics, Stock Exchange market, Finance and Administration, GPS tracking and Fleet Management, Customs Borders scanning.

Contact:

Europe, Romania, Buchar

0040.747.02.01.02

mecumihaisorin@gmail.com

mecu.sorin

in linkedIn profile

Q github

Enthusiast about Machine Learning

Age: 40 Citizenship: Romanian Married, 1 child Cat AB driving license

Current Status

Immediately available - Searching for the next project to be excited about.

Skills

Extensive experience in finding practical working solutions to business problems.

Described as *reliable, friendly, creative, enthusiast* and *efficient*. Having a good grasp of Design Patterns, DDD, BDD and TDD. Charcterized by the habit to learn something new with every chance.

Programming Languages

Programming languages polyglot. List of programming languages I would like to use in future projects:

F# (5 years as hobby and 18 months in production)

Elm / Elmlang

Haskell (less than a year) as hobby

Python (3 years) as hobby

Go / Golang

C# (13 years in production)

TypeScript (5 years)

JavaScript (8 years)

Education

Deeplearning.ai by Coursera platform

Deep Learning Specialization - Certificate License DKMDM27AJZ9Z

2018

Composed by following courses:

- 1. Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- 2. Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization
- 3. Structuring Machine Learning Projects
- 4. Convolutional Neural Networks
- 5. Sequence Models

Stanford University by Coursera platform

Machine Learning course - Certificate License NNJVA7SM77QV 2016

University of Bucharest - Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science

Master's Degree, Computer Science - Artificial Intelligence 1997 – 2001

Recommendations

I managed Sorin for 18 months while at RealtyShares, and his attention to detail and work ethic were exceptional. He is deeply passionate about F# and Machine Learning / AI concepts and in practice. One event he even stayed up and online past 4am his time to participate in an F# ML hacking session with the team and F# community. Of the many arduous tasks Sorin conquered while on the team, most impressive was the migration of hundreds of thousands of financial documents from one platform to another in under a month of working on it. Fighting through inconsistent data and unreliable identifiers between documents and users, he was able to re-home every single statement. It was a pleasure working with Sorin; I look forward to the next opportunity.

Had the pleasure of working with Sorin for roughly a year. Although he joined as a remote contractor, he quickly became an indispensable member of our team. Very conscientious developer who's scrupulous about testing, domain modeling, and correctness. He wrote many of the core F# libraries at RealtyShares and contributed to several high-profile projects as a team lead. Despite this, he's refreshingly modest and welcoming of constructive criticism. Sorin does exemplary work and is a true practitioner of the craft. No question he elevates any organization's development team, and he integrates exceptionally well as a remote team member

Experience

Beside professional experience, as hobby, implemented various utility projects, gadgets (started with ATMEL microcontrollers, later Arduino) and mobile (F#, Fable, Elm, Java, Cordova, Ionic, Golang, Canopy, Selenium, Docker). I'm having a lot of fun doing various ML projects using TensorFlow and Keras.

Live-coding in F# on YouTube: Watch Sorin live-coding in F# on YouTube

IT Consultant at RealtyShares Inc.

1 year 6 months (December 2016 – May 2018) Referees: *Daniel Driscoll* and *Tracy Gonzalez* (Worked remotely the entire period)

Activity short summary:

- » Created a critical back-end layer (40k F# loc) for the platform
- » Migrated the functionality from an Orchard CMS to a new solution that we build in-house without any activity interruptions
- As a side project: I held training sessions for teaching F# to my colleagues

Technologies and framework used: F#, Suave, Expecto, Hopac, Paket, Fake, Canopy, C#, LinqToSQL, ASP.Net MVC, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Javascript, React, Redux, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, and others ...

Senior IT Consultant at MB Telecom LTD SRL

1 year 1 month (April 2015 – April 2016) Referee: Andrei Iacobita

Activity short summary:

- » Added new functionalities and enhancements to the code base of an application that is used by the Customs Borders Police
- » Optimized the database queries and removed redundant calls, greatly reducing the response time
- » Augumented the testing platform to ease the code maintenance, fixed the bugs, improved the code coverage
- » Elaborated a tool that cope with data fragmentation, by auto-activation on the dynamic events configured
- · As a side project: programmed a small Arduino device and the associated mobile application.

Technologies and framework used: C#, TSQL, TypeScript, C++, MSSQL, LinqToSQL, ASP.Net MVC, EF, WCF, ASP.Net WebForms, Rx.Net, Azure, RxJS, AngularJs, Ionic, etc..

Solution Developer at SAS Grup

5 years 3 months (September 2009 – November 2014) Referee: *Adrian Dinu* (Worked remotely over 4.5 continuous years)

Activity short summary:

- » Created a complex platform (from the services to the UI, everything except database queries and GPS devices specific logic) that provides fleet management solution as a service (biggest in Romania, that is used by companies like Coca-Cola, Orange, Vel Pitar). Analyzed, provided and presented, in various forms, the data collected by the GPS devices mounted on the cars.
- One of the side-projects was to reverse engineered the API of a personal tracking device, by sniffing the serial communication, to create a configuration application (to remove human errors and to reduce the time needed from 8 minutes to less than 1 minute per device).

Technologies and frameworks used: C#, TypeScript, JavaScript, TSQL, WCF, WPF, WWF, Silverlight, WinForms, ASP.Net WebForms, ASP.Net MVC, Telerik, Unity IOC, OpenLayers, KnockoutJS, AngularJS, OpenstreetMaps, Leaflet, D3.js, SignalR, Rx.Net, T4, SQLite, etc..

Solution Architect and Developer at Rosal Grup SRL

2 years 5 months (April 2007 – August 2009) Referee: Cosmin Oprea

Activity short summary:

- » In a team with other 2 programmers, developed an ERP solution for a group of over 40 firms with different area of activity (street cleaning, trash recycling, electronics manufacturing, tiles manufacturing, i.a.).
- One of the side-projects was an inventory scanning application on Windows Mobile that could operate both on-line and off-line.

Technologies and framework used: C#, JavaScript, TSQL, WinForms, ASP.Net WebForms, MSSQL, MS Reporting Services, Crystal Reports, WS-Security, Windows Mobile, etc..

IT Manager at SSIF Euro Invest Vision SRL

2 years 8 months (September 2004 – April 2007) Referee: Corona Radulescu

Activity short summary:

- » Maintained the solution used by the brokers for trading on the Stock Exchange.
- » Fixed some very subtle bugs inherited in the code base
- » Improved the application data flow between the brokerage house and the Stock Exchange Authorities
- » Added new features and updated the business logic to keep up with the frequent changes of the Stock Exchange regulations.
- As a side-project started the tranzition of the platform (except the accounting application) from Access to Microsoft SQL server.

Technologies used: TSQL, Visual Basic, C#, Access, MSSQL

Solution Developer and IT Administrator at SC Magic Tic-Tac SRL

3 years 2 months (April 2001 – May 2004) Referee: Dan Plosca

Activity short summary:

- » Developed an ERP solution for a firm that provides food distribution and logistic services.
- As a high note created a driver for a POS in FoxPro, to improve the speed of sales.

Hobbies

Aikido and Chess - to keep a healthy body: "Mens sana in corpore sano"



Thank you for your patience!

Let me reward your attention with a joke: What does a redneck say before he gets injured? "Watch this!"